Time travel,
has not yet been invented.
But 30 years from now,
it will have been.
It will be instantly outlawed,
used only in secret by
the largest criminal organizations.
It's nearly impossible to dispose
of a body in the future.
I am told.
Tagging techniques, what not.
So when these criminal organizations
in the future need someone gone,
they use specialized assassins,
in our present...
called loopers.
And so,
my employers in the future,
nab the target.
They zap him back to me,
their looper.
He appears...
hands tied and head sacked.
And I do the necessaries.
Collect my silver.
So the target is vanished
from the future,
and I have just disposed of a body
that technically does not exist.
Clean.
Bonjour Joe.
Good morning Joe.
Bonjour Béatrix.
Good morning Beatrix.
How is the French?
Slow.
How is the coffee?
Burnt.
Two Jed.
Hey Joe.
Be at the club tonight?
Yeah.
Four Jed.
Bang.
Walk around.
Around the bike.
I am not kidding! Wide...
Hey, I don't...
around!
Rude.
You shit!
If you had a mama,
she didn't raise you right.
That's funny.
Because I am going to pick
your mother up later on my bike,
and I am gonna take my blunderbuss...
Hey Seth.
Hey Joe.
That's new.
Yeah, thanks.
Goddamn thing won't fucking start.
So you going to the Belle?
Hey man!
So you bought a slat bike?
Yup.
How much that thing set you back?
How much?
I was gonna pull up in it tonight.
Well, congratulations.
You are pulling up with me instead.
Don't.
If we are going in, don't do that.
Chicks dig TKs.
They do not.
Yes, they do.
It's tacky. Don't do it.
About 10 percent of the population,
has this TK mutation.
When it first appeared, everyone thought
we were gonna get superheroes.
But it turns out this was it.
Now it's a bunch of assholes,
think they are blowing
your mind floating quarters.
It's like this whole town.
Big heads,
small potatoes.
Full house tonight Joe.
We will stick backstage.
Just meeting up, in and out
Packing your blunderbusses?
Hardly. Right Seth?
I am with Joe.
Just meeting up, in and out.
Go on.
Suzie!
Hey!
You working a shift tonight?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Have a gat man bought me out
already for the night.
Oh.
Sweetie, I have got to work.
Hey Joe.
What?
Zach.
He is in there right now with Abe.
For what?
Closed his loop.
No shit?
There is a reason we are called...
loopers.
When we sign up for this job,
taking out the future's garbage,
we also agree
to a very specific proviso.
Time travel in the future,
is so illegal,
that when our employers want
to close our contracts,
they will also want to erase,
any trace of their relationship with us,
ever existing.
So if we are still alive
30 years from now,
they will find our older self,
zap him back to us,
and we will kill him
like any other job.
This is called closing your loop.
And you get a golden payday,
you get a handshake,
and you get released from your contract.
Enjoy the next 30 years.
This job doesn't tend to attract the most...
forward-thinking people.
So we...
celebrating?
Yeah! Yeah!
Look out!
Shit.
Jesus.
Fuck Joe.
Envie d'être en for me.
Want to feel fine.
Bonjour Joe.
Good morning Joe.
Ravi de...
glad to...
de te voir Béatrix.
to see you Beatrix
Oh la la.
What's that, fourth loop closed this month?
Loop closed. Here we go.
Loop closed, baby!
Yeah.
Seth?
Jesus.
They could be here any minute.
Are they here?
No. Who?
Christ.
Joe, Christ!
What are you doing?
Give me the gun.
Right.
That's smart.
Get away from the window.
Christ, Joe.
Just quiet down.
You can protect me a little, right?
Just so they don't...
What did you do?
Oh jeez.
This is like a nightmare.
This is a nightmare.
I knew then what he did,
so I don't know why I asked.
What did you do?
He...
He was singing.
Through the gag and sack,
but I could hear the tune.
Deep memories,
my mom...
in a dark room,
taking care of me, singing that tune.
Once I knew...
he was me...
I...
Joe, I could not.
I could not. I had to see.
He told me...
I remember, he told me,
there is a new...
holy terror boss man in the future,
and he is closing all the loops.
The Rainmaker, they call him.
He told me it.
Then he wanted a cigarette.
So...
I untied him,
and he gives me this look.
And he just starts running.
I had my blunderbuss,
so I know I have got about 15 strides
till he is out of my range.
And they come and they go,
and I just watch him till he is gone.
This is called letting your loop run.
It's not a good thing.
What do I do?
You are the only friend I have got, Joe.
You have got to help me.
You are a fucking idiot coming here.
You can't be here.
I will give you some money that will...
Joe! A little money?
Where am I gonna go?
You hop a freight train.
You beat it the hell out of town.
Just don't move.
Tell Court, watch the window outside.
You got it, window.
Kid Blue, Joe!
Come on!
Just a minute!
Open this goddamn door!
I can't do anything for you, Seth.
You have got to hide me! Please, Joe!
Please hide me!
Please Christ!
Please buy me some time
and then I will go!
Please?
You gonna make me blow this door down?
Yeah, hold on!
Please?
Move.
Come on, Joe! Open up!
Jesus.
That took a while.
You think it's easy looking this good?
Tye is gonna watch your apartment
while we go have a talk with Abe.
There is coffee in the tin.
Thank you.
Give me two minutes.
You know why they call that pea
shooter of yours a blunderbuss?
Because it's impossible to hit
anything farther than 15 yards.
Impossible to miss anything closer.
It's a gun for fuck-up turkeys.
Not like a gat.
A gat...
has range.
Accuracy.
Kid, cut it out.
Don't blow your other foot off.
Fuck!
What the hell is going on out there?
How you doing, Abe?
Hey, Joe.
You didn't shoot your other foot off,
did you Kid?
Alright.
My great-grandfather told my grandfather.
Men are like spiders.
It's the little ones you have
got to be careful of.
Don't know I agree with that.
Yeah?
What the fuck did my great-grandfather know?
This man is from the future.
He was sent back here by the mob,
a one-way ticket to run the loopers.
That's low effort, even for Abe,
so to pass the time
he recruited some real muscle,
the gat men.
Now he runs the city.
Any other city,
that would be impressive.
How can you kids stand
to wear those chokers?
Cravats?
Ties.
Ridiculous.
You are aware we don't have a dress code?
Fashion.
You know...
Well, you don't know.
The movies that you are dressing
like are just copying other movies.
These goddamn 20th century affectations.
Do something new.
Put a...
glowing thing around
your neck or use rubberized...
Just be new.
Ok.
It was nice chatting with you Abe.
I do like you Joe.
But we are sure enough,
that Seth paid you a visit.
We have to do something about this.
Seth?
You are expecting we are gonna break
your fingers with a hammer,
or something awful.
But, I am gonna defuse
that tension right now.
That's not gonna happen.
What is gonna happen,
is that I am gonna talk for a little.
Not even that long.
And you are gonna give up your friend.
My friend?
Seth? Sorry I am...
confused.
Well, then I will talk a little.
You know,
you were the youngest looper I ever hired.
You looked goddamn ridiculous, they said.
Blunderbuss up to here on you.
They brought you in.
I forget what for.
Watch shop.
Yeah.
You rolled one of our fronts, a watch shop.
And they had you, you know.
This kid,
like an animal. But you...
looked at me,
your hair stuck to half your face,
just one eye looking at me.
I could see,
like seeing it happen on the TV,
the bad version of your life.
Like a vision,
I could see...
how you would turn bad.
So I changed it.
I cleaned you up...
and put a gun in your hand.
I gave you something that was yours.
I am grateful for that, Abe.
And I remember that kid.
And I think if you ask yourself,
you ask who would I sacrifice for what's mine?
I think Seth would be deep
and cozy inside that circle.
I will show you how much I know you.
I am not even gonna break you.
I am just gonna...
set you back a ways.
We know that you have been
stashing half your bars.
Which is smart, no law against it.
You are gonna get out.
You are gonna go overseas, right.
Studying up your Mandarin?
French.
French?
You give him up...
or you give us half your stash.
You willing to dump your silver in the dirt
for Seth?
You are gonna kill him.
Not if we can help it.
Be too cataclysmic a change for the future.
What we will do is dangerous,
in that regards, though not
as dangerous as killing him.
On top of which a man from the future,
runs free long enough this...
time travel shit...
fries your brain like an egg.
Why the fuck French?
I am going to France.
You should go to China.
I am from the future.
I am going to France.
You are going...
The floor safe, under the rug.
Six seven four two.
It's the little ones that get you.
Why don't you kill an hour, Joe.
On the house.
Call the doc.
Wait.
Wait!
I can't remember my mother's face.
She used to run her hands...
through my hair.
Just like this.
I think I just let my best friend
For silver.
Shit.
Yeah.
Sorry.
I am gonna give you some money.
I have been stashing my silver,
for years and I am gonna
give you half of it.
You can raise your kid right.
You wanna give me half your silver?
Silver's got strings.
I got my job.
You got yours.
It's sweet of you to worry
about me, but I am doing fine.
Why don't we just stick
to services rendered.
Is this what you want?
Shit!
Then it just becomes a mess,
like a pig fucking a football.
You know what I am saying.
Let's finish this up.
There is 24 there.
I am keeping count.
Two more trips, should just do it.
Goddamn it!
Listen Kid, I am sorry!
Tell Abe, I am gonna fix this!
Tell him I am gonna find,
my loop and I am gonna kill him!
Tell...
Motherfucker!
Shit!
You got any aspirin?
All of them, please.
I will take that coat too.
What are you doing?
Joe, I told you to run.
Don't do it, you idiot.
Hurry up, Blue!
That's the second loop
we had run this week.
It's getting endemic.
Fucking Kid Blue.
About two more trips should do it.
Shit.
You stupid little shit.
Pound the pavement,
sweep the train yard.
Every second that passes is bad.
Get on it.
Stupid little shit.
I can fix this.
I can find him!
Go home.
Let the grownups work.
Kid Blue.
You bastard.
How do I find you?
Coffee?
Please.
Black.
And some water.
Anything else?
We eating?
I ordered something.
Steak and eggs.
Rare and scrambled.
Two steak and eggs, coming up.
Must hurt.
I was not sure you would remember her.
I put it together.
Clever.
You know,
there is another girl
who works here on the weekends.
Jen?
Right.
Less letters.
That had be better.
Pour vous.
For you.
Merci.
Thank you.
How is your French coming?
Good.
You gonna tell me I ought
to be learning Mandarin?
I never regretted learning French.
Je sais tu caches une arme entre tes jambes.
I know you have a gun between your legs.
No? Well, you will get it eventually.
Obviously.
Alright, listen.
This is a hard situation for you,
but we both know how this has to go down.
I can't let you walk away
from this diner alive.
This is my life now.
I earned it.
You had yours already.
So why don't you do what old men do...
and die?
Get the fuck out of my way.
Why don't you take your little gun out
between your legs and do it?
Boy.
It's hard staring into your eyes.
It's too strange.
Your face looks backwards.
So you know what's gonna happen?
You have done all this already, with me?
I don't want to talk
about time travel shit.
Because if we start talking about it,
we are gonna be here all day,
talking about making diagrams with straws.
It doesn't matter.
I hurt myself, it changes your body.
Does what I do change your memories?
It doesn't matter!
My memory is cloudy.
It's a cloud.
Because my memories
are not really memories.
They are just one possible,
eventuality now.
And they grow clearer...
or cloudier as they become
more or less likely.
But then they get to the present moment,
and they are instantly clear again.
I can remember what you do
after you do it.
And it hurts.
So even when we are apart,
you can remember what I do after I do?
Yes.
But this is a precise description of a fuzzy...
mechanism.
It's-It's messy.
All I know...
I know two things.
I know what's happening in my head.
And I know that you are gonna meet her.
Who?
She is gonna save your life.
For a long time, she thought we...
We would have a baby.
She would have been a great mother.
She wanted it so much.
Yeah, but she...
How...
You said she saves my life?
Yes.
Let's take a look at your life.
You are a killer.
And a junkie.
A fucking child mentality.
What's mine.
My life. Save your life.
You are asking me how?
The question is why. Why would
someone sacrifice their life?
They have wasted...
Cut your high and mighty bullshit.
I don't need my life...
Shut your fucking child mouth.
You are so self-absorbed and stupid.
And she is gonna clean you up
and she is gonna...
You are gonna take her love...
like a sponge.
And you think maybe
I am clear of the past.
Maybe I am safe.
Yesterday.
Yesterday what?
Thirty years from now...
is yesterday.
You are not gonna remember it.
I am gonna tell you what happens
to this beautiful woman,
who saves your worthless fucking life.
Have you heard of the Rainmaker?
Yeah, Seth said that night.
New boss in the future?
He used the words holy terror.
Yeah.
A reign of terror.
Mass executions.
Vagrant purges.
Everywhere at once.
Legend is the Rainmaker
came out of nowhere.
In the span of six months,
he took total control
of the five major syndicates.
That had take an army.
He didn't have an army.
The story is that he did it alone.
Alone alone.
So how did he do it?
That's the mystery.
There is no pictures of him.
Even if it is a him.
It's insane.
There are stories
he has a synthetic jaw,
saw his mom shot, shit like that.
Word spread through
the ex-looper grapevine
because the first thing he did was
start closing loops.
All of them.
You know what this is?
This number?
Dale, wait. Slow down.
It could lead us to the Rainmaker, Joe!
It's in the hospital records.
Write this down.
0, 7, 1,
5, 3, 9
0, 2, 9, 3, 5!
This is a piece of identifying
information on the Rainmaker.
He is here.
He lives here, now.
In this county.
And I am gonna use this to find him.
And I am gonna kill him.
I am gonna stop him from killing my wife.
Fuck you.
And your wife.
None of this concerns me.
This is gonna happen...
it happened to you.
It doesn't have to happen to me.
You got her picture right there
in my watch, let me see it.
Show me the picture. As soon
as I see her,
I walk away.
I will fucking marry someone else.
Promise.
So when I see that picture that...
fog inside your brain should just...
swallow up all the memories, right?
She will be gone.
If you give her up,
she will be safe.
Give her up?
Yep, give her up.
You are the one that got her killed.
If she never meets you, she I's safe.
You don't understand.
We don't have to give her up.
I am not gonna give her up.
I am gonna save her.
Get to the fields.
We can lose them in the fields.
Hop a train.
Get out of town!
What the hell is everybody doing?
You wait for my signal!
Out back! He is running!
He ran out the back!
Shit!
Alive!
Fuck! Shit! Come on, come on!
Come on, you piece of shit!
Come on!
Get the tracker!
The tracker!
Go! Go!
Fuck! Fuck!
Shit.
Come on, baby. Time to get up.
Listen up, fucker!
I have shot,
and buried,
three vagrants in the past year!
So I don't care...
what hobo sob story you have got.
I get a dozen a week, pal.
It cuts no cash with me.
But if you show your face here again,
I will cut you the fuck in half!
Well,
you found him.
Tracking Seth's bike,
that was clever.
Then you rustled up a posse
and went out to get him.
I could do it again.
You can fuck up again?
Really?
I have got too much riding, Kid.
I can't afford a fuck-up
playing cowboy.
Put your gat on the table.
I wanted you to say I did good.
That's all I wanted.
This is all I have.
Please give me one more chance?
I will bring him here alive,
and hold him.
And you can put a bullet
in his brain yourself.
No!
Get off me! Get off me!
Hey, who is there?
Stop right there!
I will shoot you.
You stop! Stop right there!
I am telling you to stop!
You stop!
Head is splitting apart.
My head.
Hey.
Look up at the light.
Look up at me.
How long since you dropped?
Dropped?
Dropped.
A day.
I can't feel my legs.
You are going through withdrawal,
you fucking junkie.
You got to help me.
I am gonna die.
I am thirsty.
Water.
Water!
Thirsty...
Cid!
Come inside, baby.
Who is that man?
He is just a vagrant baby.
No, he is not.
Yeah?
His shoes are too shiny.
Aren't you a smart monkey.
Is he sick?
Yup.
Will he get better?
Yeah.
Promise?
Just go to sleep, ok, baby boy?
Night, sweetie.
Night, Sara.
Hey!
The first time I saw her face.
First time I saw her face.
Look at me.
No.
The first time I saw her face.
The first time I saw your face.
Morning monkey.
Do you want something to eat?
The man is up.
Is he staying here now?
No.
Toss it.
I am about to finish cleaning it.
Put it down.
How are you feeling?
I would say I am at 30 percent.
You take it slow, by the end
of the week you will be at 50.
I took you in so you would not die.
You are not gonna to die.
So just take the morning to rest,
then get off my farm.
I can't do that.
I am sorry?
I need to stay here for a little while.
I am not cool with that.
I am sorry.
Well sorry to you.
You just lost your take the morning
to rest privileges.
Get off my farm.
No.
You could not scare a retarded
hobo with that. Literally.
This is a Remington 870.
One blast could cut you...
In half. That's...
telling.
You are holding a gun.
I say I am not afraid,
so you describe the gun to me.
It's not the gun I am not afraid of.
What are you gonna do, shoot in the air?
That's scare me got.
You would not let me die,
you are not gonna kill me.
So now I saved your life
that makes me weak?
I am not a threat to you...
or your boy.
I need to be on your property.
I would rather there is no contact at all.
I am gonna stay in the fields.
Just there is one thing I need you to do,
then you will never
have to deal with me again.
Please verify for me is your house
on the map, so I am in the right place.
What's this?
It's a map.
Yeah that's my house.
Why is it marked?
Ok, doesn't matter. Look.
I am gonna be out of the barn in an hour.
If you can spare it,
I am gonna take this canteen.
Is there somewhere I can fill it?
This number, how did you get this?
That mean something to you?
What?
Hey! Hey!
Hey!
You are right. I am not a killer.
But I am fine with how a blast of rock
salt to your face won't kill you.
Now you are gonna tell me...
who you are,
and what the fuck
you are doing on my farm?
Ok.
Time travel has not been invented yet,
but in 30 years, it will have been.
It's gonna be used
by these criminal syndicate...
You are a looper?
I can't go back to the city because Abe,
the boss,
his men will be searching for me 24/7,
until they find me or find him.
All I have got is that map.
He had three houses marked on it,
yours is one of them.
I know he is coming here.
So you know about loopers?
You know what we do?
So he is coming here...
to murder my son
because he thinks he might be this...
Rainmaker?
And once he kills the
Rainmaker, what happens?
I think...
he thinks...
if he killed the Rainmaker,
he never would have been sent back.
So he would just vanish.
He would disappear just like he appeared.
He would be back with his wife.
Who is he,
this guy you let run?
Just some random guy from the future?
He is just somebody. You know...
what the numbers mean?
This is Cid's birthday
and this is the med code of
the hospital he was born in.
How many kids were born in that
hospital that day with your son?
Like, two?
Sounds right.
Three kids,
three houses marked on his map.
One of them is the Rainmaker.
He doesn't know which.
What's he gonna do?
God.
Can he really do this?
Think about what doing this would fix.
What he thinks it would fix.
If he comes here, will you stop him?
I am asking, can I trust you?
I don't care if you trust me.
I don't care about your son.
I lost my life. I kill this man,
I get it back.
He will kill the other two kids
and come here last.
Put off facing me.
All this goddamn cane leaves us blind.
He can get within 50 yards of this place
without a hawk spotting him.
What makes sense is we burn the fields.
Level them.
How much gas you got in that barn?
No, you can't burn down my cane fields.
This stuff is half dead anyway.
It's the seed for next year.
It's not gonna happen,
you fucking nut.
Listen, use what you need
and set up anywhere.
But one thing.
I don't want you talking to Cid.
I watch my son, you watch the cane.
That's the deal.
Good by me.
Fine.
Jesus.
Alright, hold still.
It's easy for things
to get infected on a farm.
Start falling off.
Pussy.
I am out here and you are in the house.
We need a way to communicate.
There is a dinner bell in the barn.
You can ring that
if someone is coming here.
Dinner bell. We need...
buzzers,
walkies or something.
I don't know what we have got,
but I will look.
Cid!
How is the math coming?
I want to help the man.
Help him with what?
I could help him with my toys.
No.
Let me talk to you.
I need you to stay away
from that man. Ok?
You just let him do his thing,
but stick with me.
Ok?
Is he not good?
Well, we are gonna see what he is.
Alright, but I need you to stick with me.
Good boy.
Hand me that Phillips.
Tell me if you hear her coming.
What are we doing here?
Commundication.
But I need to make it stronger.
And how do we do that?
Bigger battery.
Smart.
Do you kill people?
Let's say I kill people.
With your gun?
You want a gun like mine?
Yeah.
What are you gonna do with it,
pole vaulting?
It's bigger than you.
Stop bad things from happening.
Shit!
So...
how long you and your mom
been out here on the farm?
She is not.
She is not what?
Sara doesn't know,
but I remember my real mom.
When I was a baby,
I could not stop it.
Could not stop what?
I could not stop her from getting killed.
I saw it,
but I could not stop it.
I was not strong enough.
You should...
You should talk to your mom about this.
She is not my mom.
She is a liar.
Spotted him coming out of a sewer tunnel
on the west end.
He is on the run.
Think he is heading to the west
on Talbott Street,
possibly to Whore's Alley.
We have a visual.
You can't take that thing out
with a plow or something?
Listen, I found a...
In the barn, I found some
parts and I made a...
a thing.
Here.
So if you see something just...
push that.
When?
Last night he woke me up.
Don't tell him I told you. He didn't...
You said you were his mom.
Yeah.
He told me you are not.
He said that?
Yeah.
If he is not your son, who is he?
He is my son.
I had Cid when I was 22.
But I didn't want to give up
my life in the city.
So I dropped him here...
on the farm...
with my sister and she saw...
how I was living, so she took him.
And my sister,
she raised him.
She loved him.
He called her Mom.
How did she get killed?
Jesus Christ.
He remembers it.
You have got to talk to him about it.
I told you one thing.
I told you to stay away from my son.
He asked about my gun.
Stay out of it!
And stay the fuck away from my son!
Where does fifty-six go?
Good.
You are smart.
Twenty-one?
How long can you not sleep?
I don't know.
Probably a while.
It's a good question.
Where does it go? Come on.
Good.
Thirty-two?
You should help Joe watch.
Joe?
Because he can't stay awake all the time.
Isn't our business. Ok?
He is keeping us safe.
Let's do this now, ok?
You have thirty-two there.
I know you know this one.
No. eight times three is what?
Thirty-two.
Eight times three is what?
I want you to count three eight.
Eight.
Sixteen...
thirty-two.
Are you telling me
you want alone time?
No.
Then why don't you put that
where it belongs?
Alone time.
He is protecting us
because you can't do it.
Ok. I told you to stay away from him,
didn't I?
I never did anything.
Do you think I am stupid?
So?
I told Joe to leave...
You do what I tell you, Cid!
You can't tell me what to do.
You are not my mom!
You are a liar!
You are gonna get killed
because you won't stop lying!
Sara you are lying to me!
Cid, calm down.
I hate you Sara!
You are lying to me! I hate you, liar!
Cid...
I hate you! Liar! You are lying!
Calm down. Calm down.
Liar!
You are not my mom!
You are a liar!
Liar!
I am sorry.
It's ok, sweetie.
Holy shit.
Evening, ma'am.
Evening.
How can I help you?
You can start by accepting my apologies,
are the hour.
Hope I didn't catch you at supper.
No that's fine.
I have been walking between
empty farms all day in the hot sun.
Thought I would just...
tick this one off the list.
Not have to come back tomorrow.
What's this about?
You alone here ma'am?
My husband should be back
from the city any time.
Happy to hear it.
Could I trouble you for some water?
I will get you some.
You can take the glass with you.
Actually ma'am,
my business today,
this...
ticking off the list business,
is gonna require me coming in,
if that's alright.
Will you tell me what this is about?
I will, yes.
Can I come in?
Madam?
I am a deputized police officer,
looking for an escaped criminal.
Anyone through here in the past two days,
vagrants?
Vagrants are always passing,
nobody near the house.
This man, here?
He is young. No.
We are looking for his father too.
Similar looking build, late 50s,
may or may not be traveling together.
Do you recognize them?
No.
Keep them.
Your kids with your husband?
Yeah, just one.
How old?
Ten.
Ten...
I am gonna show you
the barn and house.
And then you can be on your way.
I took the liberty with your barn.
Apologies.
So...
the house.
Ten, you said?
Your boy?
Yeah.
And your husband?
I have just got to check in,
with the home office.
So the boy is in the city with his father.
When they getting back?
Could not tell you.
This goddamn thing.
I never get a signal this far out of town.
Piece of shit.
Ok.
Here we go.
Is this man dangerous?
He shoots men down for a living.
He is a stone-cold killer.
My boss has half the city looking for him.
Half the city and me,
so...
And if you find him,
there is a hell of a price.
Chunk of money like that,
you should think on it.
I will.
Alright.
Show me upstairs.
There is drafts in the house.
My grandad built this tunnel
when the vagrant raids got bad.
Nana said he was nuts.
Thank you Grandad.
That was not the man.
No.
It's funny.
I know that guy, though.
His name is Jesse.
I like him.
He is good.
He is gonna go away once
he doesn't find me.
He won't hurt your mom.
Sara.
Where is your mom?
Where is my mom?
She...
gave me up.
I was younger than you.
We were vagrants,
and she was alone.
For a long time I thought she was stupid
for getting on the drugs she was on,
but now I see she was just...
so alone.
It's what she had.
She sold me...
to a panhandle gang.
I got away and I ran...
and ended up on this train.
I remember I was sitting there,
in an empty car.
And I saw myself over and over again,
killing those men that bought me,
that got my mom on what she was on.
Just...
finding them and tearing them apart.
Saving my mom.
But you didn't.
No, a man in the city found me,
put a gun in my hand.
Gave me something that was mine.
That's just men trying to figure out
what they would do,
to keep what's theirs, what they ave got.
That's the only kind of man there is.
I am not gonna let Sara get killed.
I think we are clear.
Sara!
Baby.
All working girls,
yeah?
This whole block
and a couple of blocks over.
Hello, Joe.
If you want to check those, too,
I can arrange.
I am an arranger, stranger.
If you don't see what you want to see,
no refunds.
What?
What happened?
That's pretty good.
In the city, young guys would...
hit on me by...
floating fucking quarters.
And I would not tell them I was TK but...
I would keep their quarters down.
This one guy,
just busted a blood vessel
in his eye trying to get it up.
He is you.
Your loop.
You lied to me.
But I know you are not lying
when you say you are gonna kill this guy,
your own self.
You protected Cid,
from that gat man.
Tomorrow...
you...
Yeah...
He saved your ass, didn't he?
He saved my ass. Yeah.
He is a...
He is a good kid.
Yeah, he is.
You know, when I came back,
after my sister died,
I remember seeing him...
for the first time in two years,
just sitting on the porch.
I drove up...
crying. I had been at this...
party all night in the city,
when I got the call...
so I was wearing this...
ridiculous party dress.
All my ridiculous shit.
And I don't know if he...
even remembered me, but...
but he looked at me...
I abandoned him.
I abandoned my baby.
And I have seen so many men in the city,
who I look in their eyes
and they are just lost.
So whether he loves me back or not,
as long as I am...
there to raise him,
he is gonna be taken care of.
He is gonna be safe.
He is never gonna get lost.
Hello Joe.
Jesse.
Put this down...
and let her go.
Sara, Jesse here is the best
shot with a gat that I know.
When he lets you go,
just sit on the couch.
Don't do anything stupid.
He is coming here Jess.
My loop is coming here.
I got to take you in.
I got 948 bars of pure silver.
I close my loop,
I get right with Abe.
Whatever he gives back,
I will split it with you.
Was that your plan?
Ok, take all of it.
Are you delusional?
You ain't getting right with everyone.
Long as Abe's got one gat man standing
he is gonna hunt you till his dying day.
We are gonna go now.
Gonna get in my truck...
and you are just gonna...
I am sorry.
The Rainmaker...
Cid!
My God!
Cid?
It's him.
What is he, some TK freak?
You knew.
What are you doing with those guns?
How did your sister die?
How she died?
Is that what happened to her?
No!
He kill her like that?
No, listen to me.
He was climbing a bookshelf.
Ok, and it fell back on him.
He can get scared. It exploded.
Jesus frigging...
One day he will learn to control it.
Yeah I know he will,
imagine what he is gonna do!
If he did good with it, though.
If he grew up with me raising him.
If he grew up good...
He doesn't.
You stay away from him Joe!
Cid!
Cid stay away from Joe, baby!
Follow me, baby!
Come to me. It's ok.
It's ok, baby.
Right now two things have happened.
My loop knows Cid is the kid
he is looking for.
And my gang knows I am here.
That means in 15 minutes, one or both
of them is coming down that highway.
Pack up the gat man's truck
Take everything you can fit in and go.
Drive north away from the city.
Thank you.
Got everyone here, all our men.
Arm them up. Let's go.
I got him Abe. I got him.
Well, shit.
That's right, motherfuckers.
I got him.
We knew he was sweet
on it'ss own particular whore.
I checked her building...
They found Joe too
though in a farm on the east side.
That's why all the gat men are here.
The whole crew is arming
up to make a sweep.
Joe?
Fuck Joe.
Save your bullets!
I have got the loop!
Not such a fuck-up now?
I am bringing him up to see Abe.
Get this asshole!
Get that motherfuckers!
Holy shit.
Joe!
Guess I put the gun in that kid's hand?
I guess everything comes back around.
Like your goddamn ties.
Take this truck.
Take your gold and go live your life.
Nobody is coming after you.
I fixed it.
You go kill the boy.
That how you fix it?
You are goddamn right I am
gonna kill that boy!
You just got your life back.
My life?
Your life.
Becoming you.
Goddamn it!
You have lost your fucking mind!
You let this boy live,
he is gonna
take everything you have got.
And everything I got!
See what he becomes.
I have not seen that yet.
Goddamn it!
Shit.
Ok, baby, we are going.
Put your seat belt on.
Stop.
Duck down baby.
Stop, please. He can shoot us.
Stop!
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Cid.
I am sorry.
It's ok.
I am gonna get you down.
Ok, we are going into the cane.
Go. Go.
Go.
No!
No.
Cid, no.
No!
It's ok, baby.
You are ok.
It's ok.
I love you. Calm down.
Good boy.
Mommy loves you.
It's ok.
Mom.
Shit.
You did good.
You did so good. Good boy.
Ok. Listen to me.
I need you to run into the fields now.
No Mom, I don't want to leave you.
I don't want to leave you mon. No.
It's ok.
You need to go.
Go!
Move!
Move, Goddamn it!
Move.
Then I saw it.
I saw a mom...
who would die for her son.
A man who would kill for his wife.
A boy,
angry and alone.
Laid out in front of him, the bad path.
I saw it.
And the path was a circle...
round and round.
So I changed it.
Cid!
Where is Joe?
He had to go away baby.
By LESAIGNEUR
Sync & corrections February 2023